Ferdous Munshi

Date of birth: 01/03/2000 | **Nationality:** Bangladeshi | **Gender:** Male | **Phone number:**

(+60) 1111538457 (WhatsaApp) | **Phone number:** (+880) 1858247432 (Mobile) | **Email address:**

ferdousmunshi2000@gmail.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ferdous-munshi/

Address: 3640, NANADALALPUR, MATLAB NORTH, 3640, CHANDPUR, Bangladesh (Home)

ABOUT ME

I did my bachelor's degree in biotechnology at University Putra Malaysia.

Curiosity! It strives me. Challenges motivate me; I always think that everything I encounter will help myself to become a better me. I take pleasure in volunteering. It gives me the chance to try something new, learn new things, get new experiences, increase confidence, and meet new people. I believe my action have an impact and can make world a better place. Involve me, I learn.

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/02/2024 - CURRENT Narayangani, Bangladesh

PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT MANAGER GLEAM BIOTECH LTD.

- Research & Develop new market opportunities
- Monitor product performance post-launch, analyzing sales data
- Conduct cost analysis and establish pricing strategies
- Ensure products relevant industry regulations, standards, and quality requirements
- Develop and execute product development strategies

13/03/2023 - 04/06/2023 Semenyih, Malaysia

MARKETING AND RESEARCH ASSISTANT FURLEY BIOEXTRACTS SDN BHD

- Assist in promoting existing brands and services to new and existing customers
- Assist in preparing marketing plans and sales strategies under guidance
- Assist in Research & Develop new market opportunities for products and OEM services
- Assist in Follow-up on generated leads
- Other duties and responsibilities as and when requested by the company

Business or Sector Manufacturing | Website https://furleybio.com/manufacture/

10/02/2023 - 12/03/2023 Serdang, Malaysia

RESEARCH ASSISTANT IN UNIVERSITY BIOREFINERY COMPLEX, UPM (PROFESSOR TS. DR. HIDAYAH BT ARIFFIN)

- Prepare fiber for Nanocellulose
- Nanocellulose production
- PLA/CNF composite
- Polypropylene filament
- Poly lactic acid filament

Business or Sector Professional, scientific and technical activities

Department Department of Bioprocess Technology | **Address** 43400, Serdang, Malaysia |

Email hidayah@upm.edu.my | Website https://research.upm.edu.my/EB

01/05/2019 - 30/12/2019 Narayngong, Bangladesh

CORPORATE STRATEGIST SETU GENERAL HOSPITAL

- Used to plan the task need to execute the plan for launching the company
 - Planned marketing strategy

- Choosed the instrument and equipment for company
- · Planned the interior design with an architect farm

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/02/2020 - CURRENT Serdang, Malaysia

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BIOTECHNOLOGY WITH HONORS Universiti putra malaysia

Fermentation technology, Genetic engineering, Protein engineering, Bioprocess engineering, Biochemistry, Biostatistics, Molecular biology, Enzyme technology, Bioprocessing and biomanufacturing design, Bioseparation and purification, Bioprocess modelling and optimization, Nanomaterials and biotechnology, Principles of cell and tissue culture.

Address UPM, K14, Serdang, Selangor, Malaysia, K14, 43400, Serdang, Malaysia

Website https://www.upm.edu.my/ | Field of study Bachelor of science in biotechnology with honors |

Final grade 3.18 | Level in EQF EQF level 7 | National classification Bachelor | Type of credits 4 years |

Number of credits 126

10/06/2016 - 20/08/2018 Dhaka, Bangladesh

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE (HSC) Dhaka College

Address New Market, Dhaka, 1205, Dhaka, Bangladesh | Website https://dhakacollege.edu.bd/

PROJECTS

17/03/2022 - 22/02/2023

(FYP) Final Year Project

• Production of lignocellulose nanofibrils from oil palm empty fruit bunch using a pilot scale wet disc mill

DIGITAL SKILLS

Personal skills

Reliability | Good listener and communicator | Written and Verbal skills | Team-work oriented | Organizational and planning skills | Decision-making

Industrial software skills

DESIGN EXPERT | SigmaPlot14 | SuperPRO Designer 9.0 | FoldIt | Multiple sequence alignment editing (Jalview, BioEdit) | ESLint

Academic Skills

Microsoft Office | Google Suite (Doc, Slides, Form, Sheet, Drive) | Content editing tools (Canva; Adobe Premiere Pro)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **BENGALI**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	B2	C1	C2
HINDI	B1	A1	A2	A2	A1
MALAY	A2	B1	A2	A2	A2

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ARABIC	A1	A2	A1	A2	B1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

Visionary

- Problem solving
- · Decision making
- Flexibility
- Confident

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Running

- · Refresh my mind
- · Keeps me healthy
- Love challanges
- · Interested in sports and muscle gaining
- · Unconditional love for football and bedminton

Reading Thrillers

- Love the twist and turn
- Enjoy adrenaline flow
- · Love Masud Rana series from seba publications

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Teamwork

- · Easily connect with others
- Able to handle conflict
- Positive attitude
- Great listener

VOLUNTEERING

10/10/2020 - 31/03/2021 Malaysia

AIESEC in Malaysia

- AIESEC in Malaysia (Clean our plate Volunteer)
- COP (Clean Our Plate) volunteers, We raise awareness by doing podcast in social media about the food waste.
- Educated children regarding food safty, food waste, to be eco frindly etc.
- Made biofertilizer and eco-enzyme from food waste and teach others.
- Volunteered in covid-19 relief under Putra Business School (PBS)

10/02/2020 - 31/08/2021 Malaysia

Debater

- Won a debate competition in inter departments competition (2020)
- Member at SRDC (Serdang royal debate club)

Science club event organiser

- Organised events (science fair, engaging students in events)
- Encourage peers to join olympiads organised by other colleges and clubs

RECOMMENDATIONS

Dr fadzlie wong bin faizal wong Teacher/Mentor

- · Expert on separation technology
- · Co-Ordinator for the industrial training

Email fadzlie@upm.edu.my | Phone (+60) 1129056675

Assoc. Prof. Dr. Mohd zulkhairi bin mohd yusoff Teacher/ Academic advisor/ Mentor

- Head of the department bioprocess technology
- Expert on environmental biotechnology

Email mzulkhairi@upm.edu.my | Phone (+60) 142166800

PROFESSOR TS. DR HIDAYAH ARIFFIN Teacher/Mentor/Supervisor

- Final year project supervisor
- · Research project supervisor
- Cellulose nanomaterial expert

Email hidayah@upm.edu.my | Phone (+60) 126790378